This host has nothing installed, but Docker.
No Kubernetes, no F5 tooling.
In the next five minutes,
Claude Code will deploy a full F5 BIG-IP Next
for Kubernetes stack
and fix the problems it hits along the way.
One Go binary drives everything.
We build and install it,
then ask it to check the host.
ocibnkctl doctor inspects the runtime,
kubectl, helm, and the CPU and memory floor.
Here it finds a missing tool
and prints the exact, operating-system-
aware command to install it.
Claude offers to run that for us.
This is the pattern for the whole demo.
The tool reports the truth.
The agent acts on it.
Every deployment lives in a self-contained folder
called a PoC. ocibnkctl init demo scaffolds it.
Inside: poc.yaml, the single source of truth;
AGENTS.md, the operating manual Claude reads first;
a gitignored keys folder for secrets.
The agent always reads poc.yaml before it acts.
The deploy needs two customer secrets
from F5's license portal.
A TEEM activation token, the JWT,
and a FAR image-pull tarball for the F5 registry.
Without them, the deploy stops
and tells us exactly what's missing.
Claude explains where each one comes from,
and we drop them into the keys folder.
We never print their contents.
They stay out of the journal and out of every report.
Now the payload.
One command runs the whole pipeline: validate,
bring up a two-node k3s cluster
directly as Docker containers,
install cert-manager and the F5 FLO chart,
then the CNE instance with TMM in demo mode.
The first four phases finish in about a minute.
The last one, the F5 control plane reconciling,
takes a few minutes more, which we've sped up here.
With a warm image cache,
the whole deploy is about five and a half minutes.
The first run, pulling images, is closer to fifteen.
Watch the pods schedule and turn ready in k9s,
thirty of them across two nodes.
No kind, no k3d, no third-party orchestrator,
just Docker.
Real deployments hit snags.
Here a pod is stuck Pending.
Instead of guessing,
Claude runs doctor and reads the pod's events and logs,
then names the cause in plain language
and proposes the fix.
The agent isn't just typing commands, it's diagnosing.
To prove it works, we run the scenario suite.
Each one maps to an F5 how-to article,
twelve of twelve pass green.
And because cluster up installed
the kubeconfig for us,
kubectl and k9s talk to the cluster directly.
Browse the whole F5 stack live.
One command tears it all down.
Containers, network,
and it even restores your original kubeconfig from backup.
A full F5 BIG-IP Next for Kubernetes deployment
on plain Docker, driven end to end by Claude Code.
The tool is on GitHub at mwiget slash ocibnkctl.